Guide to the Argus Book Shop Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Argus Book Shop correspondence
1857-1955
1930-1944
YCAL MSS 427
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7
(18 boxes)
The Argus Book Shop Correspondence consists of the shop's "author correspondence" files holding letters between Ben Abramson and his staff and more than four hundred writers, artists, printers, critics, and illustrators. While some of the folders hold single or just a few letters, Abramson had more extensive relationships with many writers and artists, including John Austen, Faith Baldwin, March Cost, Frederic Dannay, Norman Davey, Rhys Davies, August Derleth, Robin Douglas, Joan Marshall Grant, W. G. Hardy, Claude Houghton, William McFee, Henry Miller, Frank Cheyne Papé, Louis Paul, Frederic Prokosch, William Saroyan, Harold Sinclair, and John Steinbeck. Hundreds of Abramson's typed carbon replies are present in the files; in them, he discusses business and literary concerns, along with his philosophies and opinions on a wide range of topics. While the lack of financial, inventory, vendor, and publishing records keep the collection from being a complete record of the Argus Book Shop, the correspondence files present reveal how Ben Abramson developed business and personal relationships with authors, illustrators, and shop patrons, and in particular with British authors, the obstacles he encountered while conducting business during World War II. The collection also includes, in Series II, more than forty undated literary essays, poems, and book reviews which may have been submitted for an "Argus miscellany" that Abramson often discussed in his correspondence but apparently never produced. The writings do not appear in Abramson's journal Reading and collecting, and likely date after 1938. The Argus Book Shop correspondence files were acquired by Philip D. Sang (1902-1975), a Chicago businessman, philanthropist, and collector of historical and literary manuscripts, who then donated the material to Yale.
Argus Book Shop (Chicago, Ill.)
Abramson, Ben
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Philip D. Sang in 1955 and 1956.
Custodial History
Deborah B. Covington's biography of her father, The Argus Book Shop: a Memoir (1977), reveals that Abramson's will instructed that "all records were to be destroyed and the stock sold within six months after his death" (p. 50). She wrote that "Going through six four-drawer file cabinets of correspondence was a big job. The author correspondence Ralph Newman purchased and arranged to have donated to Yale, Ben's favorite university" (p. 52), a choice likely influenced by Abramson's long friendship with Argus patron Norman Holmes Pearson (1909-1975), a professor of English at Yale University. Ralph Newman (1911-1998) was proprietor of the Abraham Lincoln Book Shop in Chicago. Philip D. Sang (1902-1975), the donor of the collection, was a Chicago businessman, philanthropist, and collector of historical and literary manuscripts. Sang appears to have transferred the bulk of Abramson's "author correspondence" to Yale in 1956, but had given a few letters the previous year with another part of his manuscript collection. Covington mentioned in a 1957 letter to Yale curator Donald Gallup that Abramson had given some of Steinbeck's letters to collectors. The New York Public Library holds three folders of Abramson's correspondence with authors whose names begin with L through Z (MSS Col. 5).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 15-18: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Ben Abramson and his Argus Book Shop
The American book seller and publisher Ben Abramson was born in Lithuania in 1898, and immigrated to the United States with his parents after the turn of the century. The family settled in Chicago, where Abramson attended the Jewish Training School, a special academic and manual training program for underprivileged children of refugees. In 1916 he took a job as a clerk at the Economy Bookstore, where he learned enough about the trade to establish his own business, the Argus Book Shop, at 434 South Wabash Avenue in 1920. The shop moved to 333 South Dearborn Street in October 1928, and in February 1940 to 16 North Michigan Avenue. Abramson sold new and second-hand books, specializing in modern literature and rare books including fine bindings, first and limited editions, and private press volumes. In addition to selling books, he was a publisher and literary agent for several writers, and was the editor and publisher of Reading and Collecting: a Monthly Review of Rare and Recent Books, which he issued from 1936 to 1938. Also interested in the visual arts, he regularly exhibited prints and paintings in his shops, and in 1942 made a notable acquisition of more than 1,300 original wood blocks engraved by Thomas Bewick.
In 1944 Abramson closed his Chicago operations and moved to New York; on November first of that year he opened the Argus Book Shop at 3 West 46th Street. By 1947 he began to suffer what would become chronic health and financial problems. Acknowledging that much of his business was accomplished through the mail, Abramson moved with his daughter Deborah Benson Covington to Mohegan Lake, near Peekskill, New York, in April 1949. However, country life held little appeal and he returned to Chicago in March 1953 to reopen the Argus Book Shop at 218 South Wabash Avenue. Deteriorating health and financial situations continued to plague him there, and Abramson died by his own hand on July 16, 1955. He was survived by five siblings, his wife Mollie, and their daughter Deborah.
Throughout his career Abramson employed several assistants who interacted with patrons and authors in person and through the mail. One employee was George M. Dashe (1904-1984), who left Argus to open his Georgian Book Shop on South Michigan Avenue in Chicago in 1940.
Scope and Contents
The Argus Book Shop Correspondence consists of the shop's "author correspondence" files holding letters between Ben Abramson and his staff and more than four hundred writers, artists, printers, critics, and illustrators; the remainder of the shop's records were destroyed following instructions he had written into his will. While some of the folders hold single or just a few letters, Abramson had more extensive relationships with many writers and artists, including John Austen, Faith Baldwin, March Cost, Frederic Dannay, Norman Davey, Rhys Davies, August Derleth, Robin Douglas, Joan Marshall Grant, W.G. Hardy, Claude Houghton, William McFee, Henry Miller, Frank Cheyne Papé, Louis Paul, Frederic Prokosch, William Saroyan, Harold Sinclair, and John Steinbeck. Hundreds of Abramson's typed carbon replies are present in the files, and discuss business and literary concerns, along with his philosophies and opinions on a wide range of topics. To many of the writers with whom he became close, Abramson freely dispensed personal advice. On the business end, his letters show that he regularly recommended and shipped literature to Argus patrons, including Alfred Kinsey and other scholars and authors, as well as searched for and obtained from other vendors books specifically requested by patrons. Contracts in the folders for John Anthony Carr and Stanley Marks reveal the existence of the Argus Agency: A Service for Writers, wherein Abramson acted "as a personal representative for authors and as an agent for any and all literary, dramatic, motion picture or other such material produced by them." The largest group of letters present is those between Abramson and the writer Henry Miller (1900-1968), which cover in detail many aspects of Miller's career, finances, and travels between 1937 and 1955. Abramson published some of Miller's writings and sold most of his publications, as well as providing a mail-order service for sending Miller (and Miller's friends, on Miller's account) his own works and new titles by other authors. With the Miller correspondence is a folder holding Connecticut Anthroposophical Society membership lists and redacted letters from people across the country who were attempting to purchase Miller's Tropic of Cancer (1938). In addition to publishing and retailing books, Abramson handled the sale of literary manuscripts for authors such as W. Somerset Maugham, whose file contains a price list of works available for purchase at Argus.
The collection also includes, in Series II, more than forty literary essays, poems, and book reviews which may have been submitted for an "Argus miscellany" that Abramson often discussed in his correspondence but apparently never produced. They do not appear in Abramson's journal Reading and Collecting (1936-1938), and likely date after 1938.
While the lack of financial, inventory, vendor, and publishing records keep the collection from being a complete record of the Argus Book Shop, the correspondence files present reveal how Ben Abramson developed business and personal relationships with authors, illustrators, and shop patrons, and, in particular with British authors, the obstacles he encountered while conducting business during World War II.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1857, 1920-1955. II. Manuscripts, 1937, undated.
Authors, American; Authors, English; Booksellers and bookselling -- United States; Bookstores -- United States; Publishers and publishing -- United States; Abramson, Ben; Austen, John; Bailey, J. O. (James Osler), 1903-1979; Baldwin, Faith, 1893-1978; Cost, March, -1973; Davey, Norman, 1888-; Davies, Rhys, 1901-1978; Derleth, August, 1909-1971; Dannay, Frederic, 1905-1982; Douglas, Robin, 1902-; Eisenschiml, Otto, 1880-1963; Fraenkel, Michael, 1896-1957; Grant, Joan, 1907-1989; Hardy, W. G. (William George), 1895-1979; Houghton, Claude, 1889-1961; McFee, William, 1881-1966; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957; Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977; Papé, Frank Cheyne, 1878-1972; Paul, Louis, 1901-1970; Prokosch, Frederic, 1908-1989; Rascoe, Burton, 1892-1957; Sang, Philip D.; Saroyan, William, 1908-1981; Sinclair, Harold, 1907-1966; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968; Tice, Clara, 1888-1973; Walton, Evangeline; Welch, Patrick; Argus Book Shop (Chicago, Ill.); Sang, Philip D. -- Ownership
- Correspondence, 1857, 1920-1955; Series I; 5.0 linear feet (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  The files contain two-way correspondence between Abramson (and his staff) and the shop's patrons, primarily occurring during the period when the store was located in Chicago. The earliest item in the collection, and a true outlier, is an 1857 demand note enclosed in a letter from author Helen Headland; otherwise, the material in the series dates from 1920 to 1955, the span of Abramson's career.
  - Adamic, Louis, 1934-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, George Matthew, 1943 Jul 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ade, George, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1939 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Hervey, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Altrocchi, Julia Cooley, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anderson, John Redwood, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Angle, Paul M. (Paul McClelland), 1940 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arms, George Warren, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Armstrong, Margaret, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Armstrong, Martin, 1932 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arnold, Julian Biddulph, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aronin, Cele, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Atwater, Montgomery M. (Montgomery Meigs), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austen, John, 1927-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Babcock, Frederic, 1943 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bach, Marcus, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bahnc, Salcia, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bailey, J. O. (James Osler), 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Balch, Jack S., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baldwin, Faith, 1934-1944 (Box 1, Folder 22-27)
  - Baldwin, Faith, 1934-1944 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - Barker, H. Neville, 1933-1938 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Barnard, Harry, 1938-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Barnes, Margaret Ayer, 1933-1941 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Baron, Joseph L., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Baronte, Gervée, 1939 Jan 6 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bartlett, Paul Alexander
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Winters, Elizabeth R.
  - Bassett, Norman, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Basso, Hamilton, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Beach, Rex, 1935 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Becker, William
    See: Miller, Henry (1944)
  - Bell, H. W. (Harold Wilmerding), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Benét, William Rose, 1933-1948 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Benton, Walter and Lillian, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Binder, Pearl, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Binns, Archie, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Blankfort, Michael, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Bleyer, Adrien S., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Blumenthal, Walter Hart, 1938 Aug 17 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Blunden, Edmund, 1937 Feb 20 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Boissevain, Eugen
    See: Millay, Edna St. Vincent
  - Bontemps, Arna, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Boschère, Jean de, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bowman, Heath, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Boyd, James, 1939 Mar 22 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Boyden, Polly, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Braden, Louise, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Bradley, John Hodgdon, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Brasher, Philip and Rex
    See: Rex Brasher Associates
  - Bristow, Gwen, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Brown, Kenneth, 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Brown, Lewis, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Brownell, George Hiram, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Brussel, Minnie, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bullett, Gerald William, 1930-1937 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Burke, Thomas, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Burr, Jane, 1935 Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Cain, James M. (James Mallahan), 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Cairns, Huntington
    See: Miller, Henry (1941)
  - Caldwell, Erskine and Helen, 1933, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Callaghan, Morley, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Campbell, Lanning, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Carpenter, Lucile Russell, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Carr, John Anthony, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Carus, Helena, 1935 Feb 24 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Casey, Robert J. (Robert Joseph), 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Caspary, Vera, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Cather, Willa, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Chappell, George S. (George Shepard), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Chevalier, Elizabeth Pickett, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Child, Nellise, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Church, Mary, 1943 Sep 2 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Clark, Herma, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Clark, Walter Van Tilburg, 1941 Apr 2 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Clarke, Ada
    See: Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen
  - Clayborn, Dean, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Coates, Robert M. (Robert Myron), undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Conason, Emil G.
  - Conklin, Groff, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Conroy, Jack, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Cook, J. B. (John Brown), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Coppard, A. E. (Alfred Edgar), 1932 Jul 25 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Cost, March, 1939-1949 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Cowles, Maud Sherman, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Cozzens, James Gould, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Crane, Frances, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Crawford, Nelson Antrim, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Cromley, Alastair, 1930 Oct 4 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Crowell, Evelyn Miller, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Culbertson, Ely, 1940 Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Cummings, Lewis Vance, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Cunningham, Scott, 1944 Jun 22 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Dahlberg, Edward, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Daiches, David, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Daly, Maureen, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Daly, Robert Welter, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Dannay, Frederic, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 101-103)
  - Davey, Norman, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Davidson, L. E., undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Davies, Rhys, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - De Camp, L. Sprague (Lyon Sprague), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - De Casseres, Benjamin, 1929-1936 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - De Vries, Peter, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Dean, Elizabeth, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Derleth, August William, 1931-1949 (Box 4, Folder 111-119)
    See also: Bailey, J. O. (James Osler)
  - Detweiler, S. R., 1932 Jul 22 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Detzer, Karl, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Deval, Jacques, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Dewson, Nelyon Johnson, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Dickinson, Stirling
    See: Bowman, Heath
  - Dillon, George, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Dobie, Charles Caldwell, 1935 Oct 25 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Dodge, Paul Hunter, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Dopp, William H., 1942 Jul 14 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Douglas, Norman, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Douglas, Robin and Viola, 1928-1944 (Box 5, Folder 130-131)
  - Draper, Elizabeth Fowler, 1944 Jul 7 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Drinkwater, John, 1933 Dec 29 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Driscoll, Charles B. (Charles Benedict), 1940 May 7 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Drury, John, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Duffus, R. L. (Robert Luther), 1940 Jun 25 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Durant, Will, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Eaton, Evelyn Sybil Mary, 1940 Aug 17 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Eberhart, Mignon Good, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Edgley, Leslie, 1940 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Edmonds, Walter Dumaux, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Edmondson, Lucia Johnson, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Edwards, Ward Hampton, 1932 Aug 2 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Eisenschiml, Otto, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 144-145)
  - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1944 Jan 17 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Engle, Paul, 1941-1949 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Engstrand, Stuart David, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1941 Nov 25 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Faherty, Robert, 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Fairbank, Janet Ayer, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Falstaff, Jake, 1930, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Fante, John, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Farmar, Constance, 1937 Nov 25 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Farr, Hilda Butler, 1943 May 26 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Faulkner, Fritz, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Feibleman, James Kern, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Feikema, Feike
  - Felman, Hazel, undated (Box 5, Folder 159)
    General note
    Holds typescript of "Uncle Sam Stands Up"
  - Ferber, Edna, 1941 Nov 26 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Ferguson, J. De Lancey (John De Lancey), 1943 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Fetzer, Hazel
    See: Falstaff, Jake
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1941 Apr 15 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Fineman, Irving, 1939-1942 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Finney, Charles G. (Charles Grandison), 1939-1948 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Fischer, Martin, 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Fisher, Vardis, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1944 Jun 21 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Fodor, M. W., 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Foster, Michael, 1939 Jun 4 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Fraenkel, Michael, 1939-1948 (Box 6, Folder 170-171)
  - Frederick, John T. (John Towner), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Freehof, Lilian and Solomon Bennett, 1942-1944 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Frost, Robert, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - George, Ernest, 1941 Dec 9 (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - Golding, Louis, 1932-1941 (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Goodrich, Marcus, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - Grant, Joan Marshall, 1940-1946 (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Gray, James, 1941 Feb 12 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Greenbie, Marjorie Latta Barstow, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - Greenslet, Ferris, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - Gregory, Alyse, 1933 Sep 4 (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Gregory, Tappan
    See: Harrison, Carter H.
  - Griswold, Francis, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Gue, Rubie T., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - Guedalla, Philip, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - Guthrie, James, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - Haberly, Loyd, 1936-1939 (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Hackett, Francis, 1940 Feb 12 (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Hall, James Norman, 1940 Jul 22 (Box 6, Folder 191)
  - Hamilton, Joseph and Josephine, 1937 Sep 10 (Box 6, Folder 192)
  - Hamilton, Patrick, 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Hammett, Dashiell, 1920-1941 (Box 6, Folder 194)
  - Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 195)
  - Hansen, E. E., 1932 Aug 17 (Box 6, Folder 196)
  - Hansen, Harry, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Hardy, Florence Emily, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - Hardy, W. G. (William George), 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 199-200)
  - Harris, Frank, 1926 Apr 25 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Harrison, Carter H. (Carter Henry), 1939 Oct 10 (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Hartley, Marsden, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Hawkins, Arthur, 1931 Jan 8 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Haxton, Gerald
    See: Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset)
  - Hayakawa, S. I. (Samuel Ichiyé), 1941, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Headland, Helen, 1857, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    Includes a Bishop Hill Colony three-dollar demand note (1857)
  - Hecht, Ben, 1939-1954 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    See also: Felman, Hazel
  - Hemingway, W. C., 1940 Sep 13 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Heron, Flodden W., 1932 Aug 5 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Heth, Edward Harris, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Hilton, James, 1934-1939 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Hokanson, Nels Magnus, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Holbrook, Stewart Hall, 1939-1943 (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Holmes, Ernest, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Hopkins, Kenneth, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Horan, Kenneth, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Horn, Edward Newman, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Horney, Karen, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Houghton, Claude, 1942-1953 (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - Household, Geoffrey, 1936-1940 (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Houseman, Laurence, 1934 Sep 20 (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - Howard, John, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1940-1944 (Box 7, Folder 223)
  - Hurst, Fanny, 1943 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 224)
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1941 Nov 28 (Box 7, Folder 225)
  - Huxley, Julian, 1939 Dec 4 (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - Hyatt, Helen, 1944 Jun 26 (Box 7, Folder 227)
  - Jackson, Joseph Henry, 1939 Feb 13 (Box 7, Folder 228)
  - Jeffers, Robinson and Una, 1930-1941 (Box 7, Folder 229)
  - Johnson, Fridolf, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 230)
  - Johnson, Osa, 1941 Dec 13 (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - Jones, Idwal, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 232)
  - Jones, Llewellyn, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Jones, Richard, 1936 Mar 27 (Box 7, Folder 234)
  - Jordan-Smith, Paul, 1931-1947 (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - Kantor, MacKinlay, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Kaufman, Charles, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 237)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1943 Mar 20 (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - Keeler, Harry Stephen, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - Keller, David Henry, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 240)
  - Kent, William, 1937 Apr 12 (Box 7, Folder 241)
  - Kenyon, Charles, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 242)
  - Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 243)
  - Kirkus, Virginia, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 244)
  - Knight, Eric, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 245)
  - Koenigsberg, Moses, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 246)
  - Kraus, Florence, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 247)
  - Krause, Herbert, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - Lamb, Dana, 1940 Apr 27 (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - Lamb, Harold, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 250)